Guide to the George Y. Shevelov Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, 1950-2001
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals, 1950-2001
    - Rothnie, Stephen, Brisbane, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Rovenchuk, Kateryna, Ann Arbor, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Rozumnyi, Iaroslav, Winnipeg, 1975-1999 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Rubchak, Bohdan Iaroslavovych, various places, undated, 1961-1993 (63 letters and postcards, some with carbon replies) (Box 11, Folder 16 to 19)
    - Rudakevych, Ol'ha, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Rudnyts'kyi, Iaroslav Antonovych, 1950-1995 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Rudnytsky, Ivan: see Lysiak-Rudnyts'kyi
    - Rudnyts'kyi, Leonid, New York, undated, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Russen, J.R., London, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Rymaruk, Ihor, Kyiv, 1993-1994 (5 letters) (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Samchuk, Ulas, Toronto, 1965-1985 (14 letters. See also: Subseries I.2: Correspondence with Organizations--"Slovo", Box 16, Folder 13) (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Samylov, M., London, undated, 1956-1979 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Savaryn, Petro, Edmonton, 1966-1993 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Savignac, David, Stanford, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Savyts'kyi, Roman, Cranford, NJ, 1978-1980 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Sch(?), Philip, New York, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Schaarschmidt, Gunter, various places, 1966-1994 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Schaefer, Claude, Montreal, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Schenker, Alexander M., New Haven, undated, 1960-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Scherrer-Dolgorouky, M., Paris, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Schin, Woo-Tae, Seoul, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Schmalstieg, William R., Pennsylvania University, 1966-1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Schmaus, A., Munich, 1952-1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Schooneveld, Cornelius H., van, Leiden, 1953-1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Sciacca, Franklin, Vienna, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Seduro, V., New York, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Selivanov, Mykhailo, Kyiv, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Semchyshyn, Myroslav, Chicago, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Semenko, (?), New York, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Senn, Alfred, Philadelphia, 1953-1957 (6 letters, some with carbon replies) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Senyk, N., Syracuse, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Serediak, Iulian, Buenos Aires, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Serbyn, Roman, Montreal, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Serhiienko, Olena, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Ševčenko, Ihor, various places, 1953-1984 (41 letters and postcards, some with carbon replies) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Ševčenko, Margaret Bentley, Cambridge, MA, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Shakhnovich, Genrih L., Bat-Yam, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Shandor, V., 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Shapiro, Gavriel, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Shapiro, Michael, 1973 1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Shatun, P.: see Holubenko
    - Shchepko, Hanna, Rutherford, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Shchitkivs'ka, Tetiana, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Shebunchak, Bohdan O., Bloomfield, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Shevchenko, Ihor: see Sevcenko
    - Sheveliov, Mykhailo, undated, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Shevelov, R., 1955 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Shlemkevych, Mykola, Elizabeth, 1952 1961 (2 letters) (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Shporliuk, Roman, Ann Arbor, 1978-1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Shtohryn, Dmytro M., Urbana-Champaign, 1975-1996 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Shuhaievs'kyi, V., 1954 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Shturman, Dora: see Tiktina
    - Shtus', Danylo, Paris, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Shumuk, Ivan, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Simmons, Ernest J. (Ernest Joseph), New York & Jaffrey, 1953-1962 (13 letters. Some with carbon replies) (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Simmons, John, Oxford, 1971 1973 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Sipovich, C., London, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Siskova, Ruzena, Prague, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Sked, Alan, London, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Skelton, R.B., Auburn, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Skendi, Stavro, New York, 1957 1965 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Skorups'ka, Marta, Munich, 1978-1987 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Skrypnyk, Mstyslav S., 1973-1987 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Slaboshpyts'kyi, Mykhailo Fedotovych, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Slapchuk, Vasyl', 1999 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Slavutych, Iar, Edmonton, 1965-1984 (16 letters; typescript of a poem) (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Slupchyns'kyi, Orest, New York, 1973 1978 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Smal'-Stots'kyi, Nestor, Lima, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Smal'-Stots'kyi, Roman, Milwaokee, undated, 1951-1961 (36 letters and postcards; 1 telegram) (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Smolii, Ivan, Takoma Park, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Smotrych, Oleksandr, Toronto, 1950-1993 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Sokil, V., Ladispoli, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Sokoliu, Liudmyla Danylivna, Kharkiv, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Sol'chanyk, Roman, Munich, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Solohub, Andrii, Paris, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Solov'ev, Aleksanrd Vasil'evich, Geneve, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Solovii, Dmytro, Saint Paul, 1950-1956 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Solovii, Iurii, 1950-1997 (14 letters) (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Solovii, Oksana Dmytrivna, St. Paul, 1950-2000 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Soproniuk, Maryna, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Soroka, Petro, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Spontak, Michael, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Stadnychenko, Iurii I., Kharkiv, 1991-1994 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Stadnyk, Elena, Hamburg, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Stamatelatos, Emilia, New York, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Stand, Christian, Oslo, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Stankevich, Ia., New Jersey, undated, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Stankiewicz, Edward, Bloomington, 1957-1970 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Starchuk, Orest Dmytrovych, Edmonton, 1957-1964 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Starosol's'ka, Uliana, New York, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Starski, Fr., Zakopane, 1964 1969 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Stefanivs'ka, Lidiia, Cambridge, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Stefanovych, Oleksa, 1950 (1 letter) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Stefanyk, Iurii (aka Klynovyi, Iurii), Edmonton, 1966-1984 (70 letters and postcards; 1 telegram) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Stender-Petersen, Ad. I., Aarhus, 1954-1962 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Stepanenko, Mykola, 1953-1961 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Stetsenko, Hryhorii Opanasovych, Donbas, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Stieber, Zdzislaw, Warsaw, 1968-1980 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Stolz, Benjamin A., Ann Arbor, 1973-1977 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Stolychna, Nadiia, undated, 1986-1998 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Strakhov, Aleksandr, 1988-1995 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Struk, Danylo Husar, Toronto, 1962-1997 (40 letters and postcards; 1 note) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Struk, Oksana, Toronto, 1980-1997 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Strumins'kyi, Bohdan, Cambridge, MA, 1972-1983 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Strutyns'ka, Mariia, Philadelphia, 1953-1977 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Subtel'nyi, Orest, 1974 1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Sume(?)-Boiko, L., Munich, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Sumegi, Angela and Zsolt, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Sverstiuk, Ievhen, Kyiv, 1981-2000 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - To George Luckyj, 1981-1983 (5 letters, including typescripts of his poetry)
      - To Iurii Shevel'ov, 1990-2000 (10 letters)
    - Svoboda, Viktor, England, 1956-1979 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Sydorenko, Oleksander, Urbana, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Sydoruk, I., Chicago, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Syl'vester, Archbishop (aka Haievs'kyi, S.), Sunshine, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Symyrenko, Tetiana, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Sysyn, Frank E., Cambridge, MA, 1982 1991 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Syvokin', H., Kyiv, 1993 undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Szell, George, Cleveland, 1966 (1 letter) (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Szenfeld, Ignacy, Munich, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Taranenko, O.O., 1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Taranovski, Kiril, Los Angeles, 1960 1962 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Tarnavs'ka, Marta, Philadelphia, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Tarnavs'kyi, Iurii, White Plains, 1965 1978 (3 letters) (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Tarnavs'kyi, Ostap, Philadelphia, 1979 1990 (See also: Subseries I.2: Correspondence with Organizations--"Slovo", Box 16, Folder 13) (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Tarnovets'ka, Liudmyla, Chernivtsi, 1973-2000 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Taszycki, Witold, Krakow, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Tatchyn, Roman Orest, Princeton, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Tenyk-Berezovs'kyi, Z., 1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Tereshchenko, Tamila, Kyiv, 1990 undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Teslia, Ivan, Ottawa, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Tetiievksaia, Liza: see Nowell
    - Thomas, George, 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Thomas, Stephen J., Garfield, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Tigrid, Pavel, Paris, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Tiktina, Dora Musiievna (aka Shturman), New York, 1978-1980 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Tkach-Bohuslavets', Lesia, undated, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Tkach, Virliana, New York, 1984-1990 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Tkachuk, Stepan, Bucharest, 1981-1985 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Todd, William M., 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Tolstoi, (?), Moscow, undated, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Topol(illegible)sk, Suzanna, Warsaw, undated, undated, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Tret'iak-Shields, Nina, Buffalo, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Trokhymenko, Iryna, New York, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Tryblins''ka, Svitlana, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Trypucko, Jozef, Uppsala, 1952-1972 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Tsarynnyk, Marko: see Carynnyk, Marco
    - Tschižewskij, Dmitrij: see Chyzhevs’kyi, Dmytro
    - Tsebenko, V., Hanover, 1951-1952 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Tsivchyns'ka, Alla, New York, undated, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Tsymbalista, Marta, Jamesburg, NJ, 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Tsymbalistyi, Bohdan, Jamesburg, NJ, 1956-1980 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Tudorkovets'ka, Iaryna, Alliston, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Tumash, Vitaut, New York, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Turchenko, Iu., France, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Tymchenko, [O.], undated, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Tymchuk, Roman, New York, 1978-1982 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Tys-Krokhmaliuk, Iurii (aka Krokhmaliuk, Iurii), Detroit, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Udolph, Jurgen, undated, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Ulbrich, Rolf, Berlin, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Unbegaun, Boris Genrikhovich, various places, undated, 1951-1971 (letters to George Shevelov and John Fizer; 26 letters and postcards, some with carbon replies) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Unbegaun, Elena, 1969-1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Ushkalov, Leonid, Kharkiv, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Vakulenko, Serhii, Kharkiv, 1997-2000 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Valiavko, Iryna, Kyiv, 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Vasilii, monk, Mount Athos, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Vas'kovych, H., Munich, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Vasmer, Max, Berlin, 1952 1962 (2 letters) (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Vasylenko, Rostyslav, Ottawa, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Verbyts'ka, Ievdokiia Havrylivna, Kharkiv, undated, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Veretenchenko, Oleksa, Detroit, 1953-1992 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Vernadsky, George, New Haven, CT, 1953-1957 (5 letters and postcards, some with carbon replies) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Vetukhiv, Mykhailo Oleksiievych, New York, 1953-1954 (9 letters) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Veyrenc, J., 1965-1971 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Vidoeski, B., Skopje, undated, 1968-1981 (see also: letters cosigned by him in Koneski correspondence, Box 6, Folder 7) (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Vincenz, A. de, Gottingen, 19811989 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Vintoniak, Ol. M., Munich, 1968-1994 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Volosova, Ol'ha, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Volyniak, Petro, Toronto, 1950-1969 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Voroniak, Oleksander, Washington D.C., 1984 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Vovk, Anatol', Edison, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Vovk, Sonia, Windham, NY, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Vovk, Vira (aka Selians'ka), 1978-1993 (32 letters and postcards; 1 note) (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Vudka, Iu., 1979 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Vynar, Bohdan, Littleton, 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Vynar, Lubomyr Roman, Kent, 1971-1974 (10 letters) (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Vytvyts'kyi, Vasyl', Glen Spay, 19781980 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Weinreich, Uriel, New York, 1953-1962 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Weintraub, Anna, 1955-1963 (see also: Weintraub, Wiktor) (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Weintraub, Wiktor, Cambridge, undated, 1954-1986 (148 letters and postcards, some with carbon replies) (Box 14, Folder 22 to 24)
    - Westfal, Stanislaw, Glasgow, 1952 1955 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Wexler, Paul, various places, 1964-2000 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Whitfield, Frank, Berkeley, CA, 1957-1988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wilbur, David E., 1966 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Winkel, Hans-Jurgen zum, Heidelberg, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wirsta, Aristide, Paris, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Woltner, M., Bonn, 1952-1975 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wordick, Frank J.F., Charlottesville, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Worth, Dean, Los Angeles, undated, 1962-1998 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Wyeth, John S., 1963 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Wynar, Liubomyr: see Vynar
    - Wytrzens, G., Vienna, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Young, David, Colorado Springs, undated, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Za(?), Alfred, 1961-1966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Zablots'kyi, Teodor, L'viv, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Zabuzhko, Oksana Stefanivna, Kyiv, undated, 1991-2001 (36 letters and postcards) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Zahariichuk, A., Winnipeg, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Zahoruiko, Iulia, Kyiv, Bonn, 1993-1996 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Zakharkin, Stepan, Cambridge, MA, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Zakharov, Ievhen, Kharkiv, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Zakrevs'ka, Iaroslava, L'viv, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Zales'ka Onyshkevych, Larysa M. L., various places, undated, 1968-1984 (14 letters and postcards) (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Zales'kyi, A.: see his letter to Oldrich Leska of 1976 in Leska's correspondence (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Zamsha, Ivan, New York, 1954-1998 (see also: his note on the Dmytro Chyzhevs'kyi letter of 1972 addressed to him in Box 2, Folder 14; and letters cosigned by him in Subseries I.2: Correspondence with Organizations--Ukrains'ka Vil'na Akademiia Nauk, Box 16, Folder 15) (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Zaporiz'kyi, Ol., 1953 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Zavel'berg-Ivanova, I., Aachen, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Zelins'ka, Nadiia, L'viv, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Zherebets'kyi, Ievhen, Kyiv, L'viv, 1992-1997 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Zhuk, Liuba, Montreal, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Zhukovs'kyi, Arkadii, Paris, 1973-1995 (see also Subseries I.2: Naukove Tovarystvo im.Shevchenka (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Zhulyns'kyi, Mykola, Kyiv, 1992-2000 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Zhuravlev, Vladimir Konstantinovich, Moscow, 1974-1992(13 letters and postcards) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Zhyla, Volodymyr, Lubbock, 1967-1989 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Zorivchak, Roksoliana, L'viv, 1991-1997 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Zuievs'ka, Tamara, Edmonton, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Zuievs'kyi, Oleh, Edmonton, Philadelphia, undated, 1956-1984 (14 letters and postcards, 1 telegram, 1 letter fragment) (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Zybenko, N.: see letter to N.Livyts'ka-Kholodna in Livyts'ka-Kholodna's correspondence (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Group letters and greeting cards; empty envelopes, undated, 1966-1991 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified (Box 15, Folder 15 to 19)
    - Outgoing letters, undated, 1950-1994 (carbon replies; arranged chronologically) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 5)
  - Subseries I.2: Correspondence with Organizations, 1951-2001
    Comprises correspondence with various organizations, including publishers, universities, Ukrainian organizations, etc. Organized in alphabetical order.
    - ACTA Congressus Internationalis Historiae et Philogiae Slavicae, Vienna, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - All Souls College, Oxford, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, New York, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - American Slavic and East European Review, New York, 1954-1957 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - American Society of Geolinguistics, Inc., New York, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Antonovych Foundation: see Subseries I.1: Antonovych, Omelian and Tetiana; and also Hal'chenko, Serhii
    - Archivum Linguisticum, 1956-1957 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Berezil': literaturno-khudozhnii ta hromads'ko-politychnyi zhurnal, Kharkiv, 1996-2000 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Blgarska Akademiia Na Naukite, Sofia, 1974-1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Board of Overseers of Harvard College, Cmabridge, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Brown University, Providence, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Byzantine Catholic Seminary, Pittsburgh, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Canadian Importers Ltd., Ukrainian Book Store, Edmonton, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Canadian Institute of Ukrainian Studies, University of Alberta, 1982 1993 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Canadian Institute of Ukrainian Studies Press, Toronto, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Carl Winter Universitats Verlag, 1967-1993 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Columbia University, New York, 1954-1973 (see also: Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Allworth, E., Belknap, R.) (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Columbia University Press, New York, 1954 1970 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Cornell Linguistics Circle, Ithaca, NY, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Delegatura UVU v Paryzhi, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Washington, DC, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Derzhavnyi Tsentr UNR, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Dnipro, Kyiv, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Dniprova khvylia: see Subseries I.1: Vintoniak, O.
    - Editorial Gredos, Madrid, 1957-1961 see Subseries I.1: Catalan, Diego
    - Editorial Mykola Denysiuk: See Subseries I.1: Denysiuk, Mykola
    - Fond Ivakhniuka, Ottawa University, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Harvard College Library, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Harvard University, 1952-1991 (see also Subseries I.1: Flier, Michael, and Herlihy, Patricia) (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Historical Bulletin, St.Louis, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Hunter College of the City University of New York, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Independent Belarussian Humanitarian Foundation "ARCHE", Minsk, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Indiana University, Bloomington, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Institut Filologii Polskiej UAM, Poznan, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Institut fur Erforschung der Geschichte und Kultur der UdSSR, Munich, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Instytut Ukrainoznavstva im.I.Kryp'iakevycha, L'viv, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Institut Ukrains'koi Movy, Natsional'na Akademiia Nauk Ukrainy, Kyiv, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - International Committee for the nomination of Vasyl Stus to the Nobel Prize in literature in 1986 see Subseries I.1: Kerch (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - International PEN Club, Center for writers in exile, Edgewater, NJ, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - International Research and Exchanges Board, New York, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - John Day Company Inc. Publishers, New York, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Journal of Ukrainian Graduate Studies, Toronto, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Kancelaria Metropolity Warszawskiego I Calej Polski, Warsaw, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Kharkivs'kyi Derzhavnyi Universytet, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Kharkivs'kyi literaturnyi muzei, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Komitet Naukovoho Kongresu v 1000-littia khryshchennia Rusy-Ukrainy, Munich, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Kovcheg, Paris, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Lambda Chapter of the National Slavic Honor Society, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Literaturna Ukriana, Kyiv, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - London School of Economics and Political Science, Carr-Saunders Hall of Residence, London, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - M.E.Sharpe Inc., Publisher, White Plains, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Mouton and Co., Hague, 1956 1968 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Musee du Louvre, Paris, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Muzei teatra, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Muzei ukrains'koi kul'tury svydnyk, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, Washington, DC, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Natsional'na Biblioteka Ukrainy imeni Vernads'koho, Kyiv, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Naukove Tovarystvo im.Shevchenka, New York, 1986-1998 (see also Kuzelia, Kysilevs'kyi, Kubiiovych, Padokh, Leonid Rudnyts'kyi) (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Naukove Tovarystvo im.Shevchenka u L'vovi, 1990 1994 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Novi Dni, 1964 (see also Subseries I.1: Dal'nyi; Volyniak) (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Ob'iednannia mystsiv ukrains'koi stseny, Philadelphia, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Ob'iednannia ukrains'kykh pedahohiv Kanady (OUPK), Toronto, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Ob'iednannia ukrains'kykh pravoslavnykh sestrytstv, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Ob'iednannia ukraintsiv Vashingtonu, McLean, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Odes'kyi Derzhavnyi universytet imeni I.I.Mechnykova, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Ohio State University, 1972-1976 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Ost-Probleme, Redaction, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Otto Harrassowitz Wiesbaden, Wiesbaden, 1961-1992 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Oxford University Press, London, 1970 1983 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Panstwowe Przedsiębiorstwo "Dom Ksiazki", Krakow, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Pennsylvania State University Press, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Polish Institute of Arts and Science of America, Inc., New York, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Polska Akademia Nauk: Instytut Slowianoznawstwa, Warsaw, 1968 1984 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Prapor: shchomisiachnyi literaturno-khudozhnii ta hromads'ko-politychnyi zhurnal, Kharkiv, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Radio Free Europe/ Radio Liberty, Paris, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Recenzija: see Subseries I.1: Grabowicz, George G.
    - Research Center for the Language Sciences, Bloomington, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Royal Society of Canada, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Russian Linguistics: International Journal for the Study of the Russian Language, Klagenfurt, 1974 1992 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Russian Review, Stanford, CA, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Seminar slovenskega jezika, literature in kulture, Ljubljana, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Seminar za makedonski jazik, literatura i kultura, Skopje, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Simon Fraser University, Burnabu, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Slavic Arts and Books, Jersey City, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Slavic Review, 1966-1978 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Slavic and East European Journal, 1957 1980 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Slavica Publishers, Inc.: see Subseries I.1: Gribble, Charles E.
    - Slavisches Seminar der Universitat Wurzburg, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Slovo": Ukrainian Writers' Association in Exile, New York, 1968-1978 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Slovo i chas. (aka SICH), Kyiv, 1991-1996 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Smoloskyp, Baltimore, 1969-1986 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Soiuz Ukraintsiv Avstrii, Vienna, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Southern Illinois University, Carbondale, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - St. Martin's Press Incorporated, New York, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Stanford University, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - State University of New York at Stony Brook, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 13)